(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-20T01:32:25.836302",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はなれないで...
Please don't leave me...
ここに宣言します
Here, I make a declaration...
愛することを
...to love you.
開演までしばらくお待ちください。
Please wait a moment until the performance begins.
ひとつ　病めるときも　健やかなるときも　ずっと
First, in sickness and in health, always...
愛を歌い続けることを　堂々と誓います
...I proudly vow to keep singing of love.
ふたつ　得意なダンスも　もっと追求します
Second, I will pursue my beloved dancing even more.
みっつ　ずっと推してもらえる　アイドルになってみせます
Third, I'll show you I can be an idol you'll support forever.
よっつめ　不安な未来も
Fourth, even in an uncertain future...
私が照らすんだ
...I will shine a light!
それでも　落ち込んじゃう日は
But even so, on days when I feel down...
思い出しているよ　みんなのその笑顔　その声
I'll remember everyone's smiles and voices.
ハッピー・ラブ・セブンティーン革命！
Happy Love Seventeen Revolution!
さんでー　まんでー　この先ずっと
Sunday, Monday, from now on and forever...
一緒だよね　約束
...we'll be together, promise?
ほらね、笑う門にそりゃきたる
See, good fortune comes to those who smile!
ハッピーバースデイ毎日がお祝い　ちゅーずでー
Happy birthday, every day is a celebration, Tuesday...
うぇんずでー　さーずでー　らっきーでー
...Wednesday, Thursday, lucky day!
生まれ変わっても
Even if I were to be reborn...
迷わずに
...without any hesitation...
君だけのアイドルになるよ
I'll become your very own idol!
何度も見つけてね
Find me again and again,
愛することを
...to love you.
ひとつ　アイドルとは
First, what is an idol?
時にあざとさが　お決まりと
Sometimes, being cute and sly is the norm,
誰かが言ってたけど　上手くできないの
...or so someone said, but I can't do it well.
ねえ　むっつめは　私から
Hey, the sixth vow is from me,
お願い聞いて
...please listen to my request.
推し変なんてしないでよね　私を見て！
Don't go supporting anyone else, look only at me!
ハッピー・ラブ・セブンティーン革命！
Happy Love Seventeen Revolution!
2026.01.10 Tokyo International Forum
[January 10, 2026 Tokyo International Forum]
Are You Ready?
Dreams in Motion New Year's Party 2026
みんなーー！
Everyone!
楽しさに釣られ
Lured by the fun,
うっかり探したら
as I searched carelessly,
知らないあれやこれ 巡り会った
I came across all these things I didn't know.
大変な挑戦も
Both tough challenges
のんびり休息も
and relaxing breaks...
支え合って想い 伝染した
we supported each other, and our feelings caught on.
見切り発車でも
Even if we start prematurely,
前を向いて
let's look forward
小さな星 浮かべて
and float a tiny star.
途切れない
Never-ending
笑い声の中を
laughter...
進もう
Let's move forward through it.
さあ 教えて ほら全部
Now, tell me, show me everything!
何回 時計の針
No matter how many times
ぐるぐる 回っても
the hands of the clock spin round and round...
話を聞くよ
I will listen to your story.
まだまだ終わらない
This dream will surely
この夢がきっと ずっと
continue forever and ever...
褪せることのない 時を 君にくれる
giving you a time that will never fade.
訪れた先で
Wherever we go,
歓迎 増えていく
the warm welcomes grow.
すれ違った風に 聞いたみたい
It's as if I heard it from the passing wind.
そして世界中を
And drawing in the whole world,
巻き込んで大行進
our grand parade...
一人また一人 加わった
joined by one person after another.
ちょっと迷って
Getting a bit lost,
道を探す
searching for our way...
双眼鏡 覗いても わからない
Even looking through binoculars, I can't tell.
迷っているのも
Even being lost...
それが良い思い出だって
You can say that's perfectly fine,
言っていいよ
as it will make a wonderful memory.
ねえねえ たくさんの
Hey, let's keep all those
思い出をこぼさないように
precious memories tightly stored
ぎゅっとしまって
so they won't spill out...
宝物 大切に
keeping our treasures safe
運び続ける
as we carry them forward.
出会えた瞬間に
The moment we met,
こんな場所があるよって
telling you "a place like this exists,"...
そっと広げ
let's gently spread it out
見せつけていこう
and show it off to everyone.
次は君のもとへ
Next, we'll head right to you.
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Go! Go! Go! Go!
さあ！
Come on!
教えて ほら全部
Tell me, look, tell me everything.
何回 時計の針が
No matter how many times the clock's hands
ぐるぐる回っても
spin round and round,
話を聞くよ
I will listen to your story.
終わらない まだ終わらない
It won't end, it won't end yet.
この夢はきっと
This dream will surely...
ずっと永遠に
...go on forever...
褪せることのない
...and never fade.
時をキミにくれる
It will give this time to you.
ラララ...
La la la...
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
みんな、手拍子よろしくねー！
Everyone, clap your hands along!
憂鬱なリズム刻んだ
With a melancholy rhythm beating,
夢はぐしゃぐしゃで
my dreams are in a jumbled mess.
夕暮れが引くけど
Though the dusk is fading,
キミにだけは逃げないよ
I won't run away from you.
ごらんかな
Look over there,
一緒にいけるかな
I wonder if we can go together?
秘密の街を
Through the secret city,
渡って行こう
let's make our way across.
深呼吸して
Take a deep breath.
落ちて分かったこと
What I realized after falling...
壮大で
...is how grand it is,
笑っちゃうくらい
it's almost laughable!
大好き！
I love it!
最高な1日を
Wishing for the best kind of day.
上手くいかない日だって
Even on days when things don't go well,
全力で歌うんだ
I'll sing with all my might!
明日の表情
Tomorrow's expression,
水に流したら
if we let it wash away,
何だってやれそうだ
it feels like we can do anything!
落書きの中に
Within the scribbled drawings,
光ってた想いを
the feelings that were shining...
キミとこうして
...I shared them with you like this,
話せたんだって
telling you about them,
誇りたいから
because I want to be proud of them.
もっと
More!
瞬いて 瞬いて
Sparkle, sparkle!
未知の展開も
Even unknown developments
悪くはないよね
aren't so bad, right?
酸いも甘いも
Both the sour and the sweet,
集めたいんだよ
I want to collect them all.
どうかな
What do you think?
成長できるかな
I wonder if I can grow?
お友達を保存
Our friends,
見つけ合おう
let's find each other!
段々と
Gradually,
増えていく
increasing in number,
この街のピースと
with the pieces of this city.
ずっと
Always,
大好物
my absolute favorite,
大好き！
I love you!
信じるまま行こう
Let's go, just believing.
楽しいが足りない日は
On days when the fun isn't enough,
一緒に探そう
let's find it together!
昨日よりも
Even more than yesterday,
加速していく
we're accelerating,
手を繋いでいて
so hold my hand.
簡単じゃない
It's not easy,
ホームの掛け声は
the cheers from our home ground.
いつもキミが
You are always
暖かく放って
sending them out warmly,
支えてくれる
supporting me.
ずっと
Forever,
導かれて光るよ
I'll shine, being guided.
みんな一緒に！せーの！
Everyone together! One, two!
ラララ...
La la la...
上手くいかない日だって
Even on days when things don't go well,
全力で歌うんだ
I'll sing with all my might!
明日の表情
Tomorrow's expression,
水に流したら
if we let it wash away,
何だってやれそうだ
it feels like we can do anything!
落書きの中に
Within the scribbled drawings,
光ってた想いを
the feelings that were shining...
キミとこうして
...I shared them with you like this,
話せたんだって
telling you about them,
誇りたいから
because I want to be proud of them.
もっと
More!
瞬いて 瞬いて
Sparkle, sparkle!
みんなでせーの！
Everyone, one, two!
そらともー！
Soratomo!
はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！はい！
Go! Go! Go! Go! Go! Go!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
おはよう！安全に今日もご挨拶。て、あれ？嘘、もうこんな時間！？
Good morning! Safely greeting you today too. Wait, what? No way, is it already this time?!
午後から予定あるのに　すぐに支度をしなきゃ　行ってきます！
Even though I have plans this afternoon! I have to get ready right away, I'm off!
慌てて飛び出して気付く　こっちじゃない！あそこだ！助けて、行きまーす！
Rushing out, then I realize: Not this way! Over there! Help, I'm going!
トラブルばっか　転んで起きての毎日です
It's always trouble, a daily life of falling down and getting up.
何でも思い通りとか　そんな美味しい話はないけれど
Things never go exactly as planned, there's no such easy way out, but...
心の曇り空を晴らす合言葉が
The magic word to clear the cloudy skies of my heart...
ほら、快晴でしょ！ずっと
Look, it's clear skies now! Always!
みんなに届けたい　歌もダンスも元気も
I want to deliver to everyone, my songs, dances, and energy!
きっと同じ空の下
Surely under the same sky,
笑顔も分け合えるよ
we can share our smiles.
ちょっと疲れちゃう時も
Even when we're a little tired,
涙が出そうな時も
or when tears are about to fall,
いつも魔法の言葉　今日も
that usual magic word, today too...
ケセラセラだから　せーの！ケセラセラ！
Because it's Que Sera, Sera! One, two, Que Sera, Sera!
みんな、ご一緒に！
Everyone, together!
今日も一日頑張ろう！カメラにマイクに　よし、準備オッケー！
Let's do our best again today! Camera, microphone, alright, preparation okay!
お水もちゃんとあるし
I've got my water ready too.
そらともさえあれば嬉しいです
As long as I have Soratomo, I'm happy.
それじゃ、今日は何をしようかな？
Well then, what should we do today?
お歌に雑談に　あ、コラボコラボ！
Singing, chatting, oh, and collabs, collabs!
みんなと笑い飛ばせば　また明日も晴れ晴れだ！
If we laugh it off together, tomorrow will be sunny again!
よっしゃー！
Alright!
みんな、声出してー！
Everyone, let me hear your voices!
ふうっと溜息こぼしてると　夜空を見上げたら
When I let out a sigh and look up at the night sky...
ぽっと満天の星たちが　キラキラ瞬いていた
The stars filling the sky suddenly twinkled brightly.
ずっと追いかけ続けたい　昨日より高い夢でも
I want to keep chasing it, even if it's a dream higher than yesterday.
もっと大きく羽ばたいて　空まで駆けていくよ
Flapping my wings even wider, I will run all the way to the sky.
そっと背中を押すような　温もりに包まれたなら
If I'm wrapped in a warmth that gently pushes my back,
いつまでも止まらないよ　今日も明日もずっと
I will never stop, today, tomorrow, and forever.
ケセラセラだから　せーの！ケセラセラ！
Because it's Que Sera, Sera! One, two, Que Sera, Sera!
みんなー！
Everyone!
新年、あけまして！
Happy...
おめでとうございます！
...New Year!
本日は、お寒い中、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today in this cold weather!
みんな、来れた？あ、来れてるからいるの分かった。あの、ちゃんと、あの
Did everyone make it? Ah, since you're here, of course you did.
安全に来れましたか？
Did you arrive safely?
えっ、今回のそらパは、えっと、私のライブ史上最大規模ということで、すごい大きな会場で
So, this SoraPa is the largest scale in my live history, in a really huge venue.
あの、ハッシュタグとかも見てたんだけど、『デカッ！』って、『デカいな、すごいな』って書いてる人がいっぱいいて
I was looking at the hashtags, and there were so many people writing 'It's huge!' and 'How big, amazing!'
私も『デカいな、すごいな』って思いながら見てました。リハーサルの時は
I was also looking at it thinking, 'It's huge, amazing.' During rehearsals...
『ここ、ここにいっぱいそらともさん来るね』って言われて
I was told, 'A lot of Soratomo will come here, right here!'
『え、でも誰もいないじゃん！誰もいないよ！誰もいない...』っていう会話をしながら
And I was like, 'Eh, but there's no one here! No one's here! No one...'
えっと、とても楽しくやっておりました。
We had that conversation while having a lot of fun.
でもみんないるね！ありがとう！
But everyone is here now! Thank you!
というわけで、今日初めてライブだよって人ー！
By the way, who is here for their first-ever live show today?!
おー、結構いるね！
Oh, quite a few of you!
じゃあ、現地自体初めてだよって人！
Then, who is visiting the venue in person for the first time?!
結構いる！ありがとう！
Quite a lot! Thank you!
じゃあ、頑張って…あ、手振るだけでいいからね、あの
Then, try your best... Ah, just waving your hand is fine, you know.
女の子ー！
Girls?!
おおー！声出してくれてありがとう！
Ooh! Thank you for raising your voices!
『キャー！』って聞こえた！
I heard some 'Kyaa's!
男の子ー！
Boys?!
おおー！ありがとうございます！
Whoa! Thank you so much!
えっ、これってあれ、ペンライトとかでできるのかな？あ、できないのかな？
Eh, can we do that thing with the penlights? Ah, maybe not?
えっ、できるかな？
Eh, is it possible?
こちらの席、赤！
This side of the seats, red!
こちらの席は、青！
And this side of the seats, blue!
真ん中は、黄色！
The middle section, yellow!
わあ、すごい！
Wow, amazing!
きれいだー！
So beautiful!
こんな感じですね。
It's like this.
今日はペンライトでも遊べちゃうということで、
Today, we can even play with penlights,
ぜひぜひみんなでも楽しんでいきましょう！
so let's all have fun together!
今日はみんなも主役だよ！
Today, everyone is the star!
いぇーい！
Yay!
ふふ、飲んでない！
Hehe, I haven't drunk it!
お水かわいい？ありがとう！
The water is cute? Thank you!
もうちょっと飲も。
I'll drink a bit more.
ふふ、ねえ、ねえ！
Hehe, hey, hey!
そう、お水だってわかったじゃん。
See, you knew it was water.
後ろも見たいから？
Because you want to see my back?
いぇーい、ありがとう！
Yay, thank you!
さ、というわけでね、今日は「いかがだったでしょうか」とはいかないので。
Now, with that said... I can't really ask, "How did you like it today?" yet...
ふふふ...
Hehe...
始まったばかり！
We've only just started!
なんですが...
But...
なんと、もう言っていいのかな？
Actually, can I say it already?
YouTubeの配信は...
The YouTube broadcast is...
なんと、ここまでなんです。
actually ending here.
ごめんねー！
Sorry!
でも、続き見たい人は、どこだろ？ここ、ここ、ここ？
But if you want to watch the rest, where is it? Here, here, here?
ここら... ここら辺から
From around... around here,
あの、チケットが買えると、
um, you can buy tickets...
買えるというか、見に来てね！
Well, not "buy," but please come watch!
チカチカしとる、すごい！
It's flashing, amazing!
というわけで、先にどんどん行ってみましょうか！
So, let's keep moving forward!
盛り上がてますかー！
Are you guys excited?!
盛り上がってますかー！
楽しんでいってね！
Have fun!
それじゃあ、盛り上がっていこう！
Alright, let's pump it up!
あの一等星のさんざめく光で
In the dazzling light of that first-magnitude star,
冒頭無料配信はこちらで終了です。
[Text: The free preview broadcast ends here.]